Register of the Burnett Bolloten Papers, 1923-1991
Hoover Institution Archives
- MICROFILM, 1932-1949. (Microfilm cabinet, Box 113-114)
  - Speeches and writings by others
    - Watson, Keith Scott, 1937 (Reel 241)
    - Xuriguera, Ramon, 1937 (Reel 242)
  - Subject file
    - Agrarian issues, 1937 (Box 243-246)
    - Antecedents, 1937 (Box 247-248)
    - Barcelona, May events in, 1937 (Box 249-250)
    - Bibliography and history (Reel 251-253)
    - Collectivization, 1936 (Reel 254-255)
    - Confederacion Nacional del Trabajo (CNT), 1937-1938 (Reel 256-257)
    - Federacion Anarquista Iberica (FAI), 1937-1938 (Reel 258-259)
    - Juventudes Comunistas de Iberica, 1937 (Reel 260)
    - Military. Justice code, 1938 (Reel 261)
    - Partido Comunista de Espaia (PCE), n.d. (Reel 262-263)
    - Rio Tinto Company Limited, 1936 (Reel 264)
    - Soviet Union, n.d. (Reel 265)
    - Union General de Trabajadores (UGT), SEE ALSO: Reel 70, 1937. (Reel 266)
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, ca. 1936-1987 (Tape cabinet, Cassette cabinet, Photo-file Photograph file)
  Phonotapes, phonotape cassettes, and photographs.
  - Phonotapes. (Reel Tape cabinet,)
    - Burnett Bolloten interviewed by Ronald Hilton, sound recording, 31 March 1987; 2 sound tape reels (Box 191)
      Access
      Use copy reference number: 46002_a_0009064
      Bolloten gives a biography of his life, though with a focus and concentration on his time in Spain.
      A second copy of this recording exists on two cassettes.
    - KPFK FM Los Angeles broadcast program hosted by Suzi Weissman, sound recording, 17 July 1986; 1 sound compact cassette (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
      Use copy reference number: 46002_a_0009062
      Suzi Weissman and Jon Amsden interview Burnett Bolloten and Mark Sharron.
  - Photographs., 14 prints, 1 negative / 1 envelope (Envelope A)
    8 prints of soldiers and civilians in Spain, circa 1936-1939; 2 prints (1 duplicate) and 1 negative of a British political cartoon, circa 1936-1949; 1 print of members of the Fifth Regiment, 1946?; 1 print of Ludwig Renn; 2 prints of previous hit Burnett Bolloten, 1987.
- Incremental materials (Box 115-117)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.